Cleaned and corrected by Lunar Team
The human mind is a vast universe.
An inner cosmos that we are
only now beginning to explore.
Our next speaker is one of
the nation's leading cosmonauts.
A rising star
in the field of neuroscience...
...and a prized member
of the Leyland faculty.
I give you Alex Nelson.
No, no, no. Thank you. No.
CBI, Rigsby. Mm-hm.
Yeah. Jane, phone for you.
Someone called Sophie Miller.
Uh...
Tell, uh... Tell her I'm not here.
Okay. I'm sorry, ma'am,
he's not available right now...
No, no, no, wait, wait.
I'll, uh, put you through.
Dr. Miller? Yeah, this is Patrick.
- Hey.
Uh, if someone is murdered
on a state university, is it ours?
Can be, if we muscle out the locals.
Why'd you ask?
Need a favor.
Sophie, Alex Nelson's
water bottle contained...
...a 10 percent solution
of hydrogen cyanide.
What do you know about that?
I know that hydrogen cyanide
is a lethal poison.
Beyond that, nothing at all.
Please, call me Ms. Miller,
or Dr. Miller, or ma'am.
Not Sophie, if you don't mind.
You're not setting
the boundaries here.
You were seen by witnesses
arguing with the victim...
...shortly before his death.
You fled the scene
immediately after his death.
A cunning plan, eh?
Since your divorce from the victim
two years ago...
...you've been arrested
for assaulting him twice...
...and made several
death threats against him.
He obtained a restraining order.
And I obtained one against him also.
Oh. Well, that's all right, then.
Didn't bother you
that Alex had remarried?
That he found happiness
with another woman?
Alex and I got past
our personal history.
We had to
for the sake of our work together.
Ah, yes, your work together
at the, uh, Stutzer Institute, right?
Which gave you ready access
to the hydrogen cyanide.
No, I had thought, being innocent,
that I don't need a lawyer.
But I can see that you
have some animus against me.
So I'll say nothing more
until I have a lawyer present.
What if we take this case,
and it turns out she's guilty?
- She didn't do it.
- How do you know?
Because she told me she didn't.
She wouldn't lie to me.
Why not?
- Because she wouldn't.
- Suppose she did.
Well, if she is guilty, then we need
to catch her and punish her.
But she's not.
Jane, I know I said I wouldn't ask,
but I'm asking.
Who is this woman?
What's the connection?
You don't wanna know.
She'll talk. She just needs time.
- To do what?
- Hey.
I'm not saying she isn't good for it.
But we don't have enough solid
evidence to support that right now.
- I disagree.
- That's your right.
But the CBI is lead agency on this.
Yes.
Strange, though, that a Department of
Justice unit like CBI is lead agency.
Because Sophie Miller called
the DOJ switchboard this morning.
You might almost think that she
chose her own investigators.
Leyland is a state university.
We automatically offer our services,
when local agencies aren't equipped.
If Sophie Miller called the DOJ,
it's a coincidence.
- Excuse me, sir.
- What is it, Drobey?
This was posted up all over
Leyland Campus during the night.
"The Animal Equality League
has seen justice served.
The blood of innocent animals
was on Nelson's hands...
...and he has paid the price
for his crimes."
Looks like there's more
suspects now.
They want the animal testing...
...in Leyland University
Science Department to stop...
...or the monster Stutzer will be next
to pay for his genocidal crimes.
Who is Stutzer?
Lewis Stutzer is one of the
world's foremost neuroscientists...
...and founder of the
Stutzer Institute at the university.
And, um, what is his connection
to the victim, Alex Nelson?
Alex Nelson and Sophie Miller
are his colleagues.
His seconds in command.
Please, understand that there's a great
deal at stake here for the university.
The Stutzer Institute is our lynchpin.
I came to see you in person
to get your firm assurance...
...that this will be handled properly.
With speed and discretion, and
iron-clad security for Dr. Stutzer.
Of course, Chancellor Stern,
you have my absolute assurance.
I will have a squad of state marshals
around Dr. Stutzer within the hour.
Agent Lisbon and her team
will handle the murder investigation.
They have the highest
clearance rate in the state.
- Good. Thank you.
- Sir.
What are you, nuts?
An animal rights case?
- You know what a nightmare they are?
- I know, I know. I'm sorry.
I didn't realize it was
an animal rights case until too late.
And that putz Stern is gonna be
a pain in the ass.
You better close this crap quick,
Lisbon.
Hey, thanks for not telling him
I made you take the case.
Lisbon? Hello?
Tell me the truth.
Truth?
Darth Vader? Luke's father.
Seriously, I've stuck my stupid neck
out for you for the umpteenth time.
I think I deserve the truth.
Why is Sophie Miller
so important to you?
She was my doctor.
She's a psychiatrist.
Yes. She was my psychiatrist.
But you hate psychiatrists.
So you always say.
She was a good psychiatrist.
She must have been, if she
managed to keep you in the room.
It was a locked room.
Oh.
I went through a rough patch.
Did a little time in a hospital.
Sophie helped me through that time.
- It's not on your record.
- No. Believe me, I...
It's not easy to do.
I know there's nothing shameful
about having a breakdown...
...but, uh, I gotta confess,
I am ashamed of it.
Thank you for being
so honest with me.
Sorry I kept it from you.
Uh...
- Shall I come back later?
- No.
Rigsby started in on the campus
security tapes. Nothing yet.
I've been tracking this
Animal Equality League.
They're all over the Internet.
They believe in animal equality.
So, you know, they're not very happy.
They've taken credit...
...for firebomb attacks
on slaughterhouses...
...and animal testing facilities.
Serious people.
I interviewed the staff at
the auditorium. No security.
Anyone present at the symposium
could have poisoned his bottle.
There are no prints on it but Nelson's.
Nobody saw where he got it from.
Brand is the same all over campus.
I'm Kerry Sheehan,
Dr. Stutzer's teaching assistant.
He's ready to see you now.
Did you know Alex Nelson well?
He was a very good man.
He was, uh...
He was a, um...
Yes? He was...?
He was a good, good man.
- Dr. Stutzer?
- Uh?
We're with the CBI.
Oh, yeah, yes, of course. Come in.
Shut that door, please. Sit down.
Terrible, terrible business.
Alex was a first-rate researcher.
Truly first-rate.
I cannot tell you how much
I'm going to miss him.
I'm sorry, Dr. Stutzer.
We wanted to talk to you
about the threats...
Couldn't have come at a worse time,
of course.
This is going to set us back
months, I'm afraid. Months.
What is it you do here exactly,
Dr. Stutzer?
Our work here is highly sensitive.
What you tell us regarding your work
is completely confidential.
All CBI agents sign
a binding non-disclosure agreement.
Very well.
I will tell you what we're doing here.
We're curing evil. Hmm.
We are banishing the devil.
We have identified
the section of the brain...
...that governs moral
decision-making.
It's a small fold of tissue
called the cingulate gyrus...
...here in the medial
part of the brain.
This is the source of good and evil.
We've learned how it works...
...and how to readjust it
when it does not work properly.
We've created what we call
a morality engine.
A morality engine?
You are skeptical.
Nevertheless it's true.
We are plumbing
the depths of the human soul.
Do you know what's down there?
Do you know
what your soul is made of?
Frogs and snails
and puppy dogs' tails?
Ah.
Humor.
Good.
Thank you, no.
Your soul is electricity.
Essence of your being...
...is a series of rapid
electrical impulses.
Morality is a binary switch system
in the brain.
And we are learning
how to control that switch system.
- Where do animals come into this?
- Well...
...we aren't allowed to poke around
inside human heads...
...until we have done
the same things on animals first.
This is Suzy.
When she first arrived,
she was quite violent.
Especially over food.
We recalibrated her
anterior cingulate gyrus...
...and now look what a happy
and generous girl she is.
Oh. Ah. Thank you.
Huh. Where'd it go?
There it is.
Is Suzy here the extent
of your animal testing?
Oh, no. There's been
other chimpanzees before her.
Rats, mice, pigeons.
Have you ever been threatened by
animal rights activists before now?
Yes, of course.
When one is a prominent scientist...
...one is sometimes
menaced by animal people.
It's always nonsense.
In this case, you must assume
the threats are very real.
The marshals will provide full
protection, but you need to be careful.
I am not intimidated.
The work we are doing here
is far too important.
That is why I have this.
In the long term...
...this technology...
...has the potential to eradicate
violence from human relations.
That is what these animal rights
maniacs don't understand.
We are trying to create a world
of peace, where everyone is safe.
From monkey attacks.
Ah.
More humor.
Hmm.
Come this way.
Well past animal testing...
...into the first stages...
...of testing on humans.
Question five: A house is on fire.
You can save,
A, a briefcase full of money...
...or, B, a homeless man.
Which do you choose?
B.
Question six...
Forget about the Animal Equality
League, we should firebomb the place.
- The guy'll put us out of a job.
- I can't see it.
Human beings are more
than just electrical appliances.
Patrick.
Dr. Miller.
Sophie.
Uh, this is, uh, Agent Lisbon.
Hello.
- I'm gonna wait in the car.
- All right.
- Thanks for getting me out.
- Oh, it wasn't me.
It was the Animal Equality League
that sprung you.
It's the thought that counts.
- How have you been doing?
- Good.
Very good.
- You?
- I've had my issues.
Well, I...
I don't know
why that should surprise me.
I suppose most patients assume their
doctors have no problems themselves.
Well, who'd consult a sick doctor?
Heh.
It's one of the reasons I left clinical
practice and went into pure research.
What are they exactly? Your issues?
I mean, what's the story with you
and Alex Nelson? Assault?
Restraining orders?
What can I say? I'm just...
...drawn to controlling but damaged
and emotionally unavailable men.
- You and Alex made a truce?
- Yeah.
But you were arguing
just before he died.
- About work. Is this an interrogation?
- No, no, I'm... Ha, ha.
I'm sorry. I was just wondering
about the logic of it all.
What logic?
You saved my life. I owe you.
I would do anything to repay that debt.
You know that, right?
But you're innocent,
so why do you need my help?
Why am I here?
Maybe I just wanted
to see you again.
Now I have.
Goodbye, Patrick.
Patrick, my name is Sophie Miller.
I'm here to help you get better.
I got a partial plate.
Which gets us a list
of about 2000 vehicles.
Take a look at the back window.
- Looks like a cat. Or a dog.
- It's a bear.
The Northwestern Oregon
state bear.
So Van Pelt cross-referenced
that vehicle list...
- ...with alumni of Oregon State.
- Which gets us five names.
All clean, no criminal records,
no animal rights activism.
All living quietly in Oregon.
But one guy sold his van
six months ago...
...to a company
based in Sacramento.
A, uh...
...company with no apparent business,
and no registered employees...
...based out of
one of those warehouses by the river.
Nice work.
We've been monitoring the building.
Nobody's gone in or come out.
- We don't know how many are in there.
- This could get nasty.
Police! Freeze!
- Let's see your hands!
- Don't move!
Yeah, I killed Nelson.
He had it coming.
And I'm gonna kill Stutzer too,
for what he's doing to the animals.
He's got it coming.
What's he doing to the animals?
Hey, can I go now?
I gotta feed the cats.
They get hungry, you know?
Then they get mad...
...and they pee
on my computer keyboard...
...and it really screws up my work.
We won't keep you here
any longer than we need to.
Now, this Animal Equality League,
tell me about it.
It's a league of people who believe
that animals should be equal...
...to humans.
I'm chair of the
League's Supreme Council.
He's crazy.
Yeah, crazy don't make him innocent.
Crazy is what makes people
kill other people.
- How did you kill Nelson?
- Poison.
- What kind of poison did you use?
- Wouldn't you like to know.
I do know. I'm wondering if you do.
Do you realize that
the real rulers of this planet...
...are insects?
Okay.
Crazy innocent, probably.
Okay. Yeah.
Keep him locked up until Forensics
have swept his stuff, just in case.
Call Mental Health Services,
have them take a look at him.
Looks like the animal rights
angle's a dead end.
- Ah.
- Back to square one.
- Grieving widow?
- That's always a good place to start.
- Yes, I think so.
- Flowers for a funeral?
I... I don't know how many
you're supposed to have...
...in a memorial service.
Is three arrangements too few?
Well, how much do lilies cost?
Maybe you should just
speak to Chancellor Stern.
He might have a better idea.
I'm sorry.
Death is so complicated.
I'm expected to answer
all these questions about everything.
- Mrs. Nelson, I just...
- Please, call me Emily.
I never really got the hang
of being called Nelson.
Can we sit?
I was just getting
the hang of being a newlywed.
And now I'm a widow.
Did you ever get any sense...
...that there was anything wrong
in any aspect of Alex's life?
No, I don't think so.
I mean, work had been really
hard lately, I know that.
Is that you?
Yes.
That's when Alex and I first met.
Cute picture.
Why was work so hard?
I don't know.
When Alex would talk about his work...
...I couldn't understand a word. And he
just stopped trying after a while.
But he had an argument
on the phone a few weeks ago.
Alex went into his office,
and I could hear him shouting.
He was so angry.
- He never shouts.
- Any idea who he was shouting at?
No. It was a woman.
Rosie, I think he called her.
Rosie?
Do you know anybody
named Rosie?
- No.
- Did you ask him about the phone call?
- I did. He said it was a work thing.
- You believed him?
Yeah.
You didn't suspect that
there was another woman involved?
No.
Sorry, I have to ask such things.
Sorry.
You have a beautiful house.
Beautiful.
Did you do the decorating?
No, it's all Alex.
He was teaching me.
He had an aesthetic.
Mm-hm.
It keeps doing that
every five minutes.
What am I gonna do?
When this funeral stuff
is done with...
...and Alex is buried,
I want you to go someplace beautiful.
Just get on a plane. Don't tell
anyone where you're going, just go.
Fly away and start building
a new life for yourself.
- Okay.
- Okay, but you promise me...
...you will fight hard against
your weakness for control freaks.
- Okay.
- Good.
Good.
I'm sorry.
She couldn't kill anyone
unless they told her to in a firm voice.
Ha. That's funny.
"Don't listen to control freaks."
"Whatever you say, sir."
Let's go see Stutzer's assistant.
Kerry Sheehan?
You think she's the mysterious Rosie?
The widow's not a true blond.
She's naturally dark.
- Is that you?
- Yes. That's when Alex and I first met.
And what?
Her hair is colored and styled
to look like Sophie...
...only younger,
who was a brunette when I knew her.
So Nelson was a control freak
like you said.
A control freak with a serious thing
for getting women to dye their hair.
Kerry Sheehan has roots.
Yes, she does.
- She and Nelson were having an affair.
- Bravo.
Don't patronize me.
Ms. Sheehan?
Kerry?
It's Teresa Lisbon.
We wanna talk to you
about Alex Nelson.
I need EMTs in 965 Elm.
He was a good, good man.
Tell them not to run the lights.
Looks like suicide.
Is it what it looks like, you think?
Yeah, how pink she was?
That's cyanide.
Causes high
blood-oxygen saturation.
Thanks.
Look at this, boss.
I found these in the garbage
upstairs.
That's Alex with the victim.
It's not a tidy end to this sad saga...
...but it is an end at least.
Thank you for all your hard work.
We're not done here, I'm afraid.
If Kerry Sheehan was a suicide...
...that doesn't make her
guilty of Alex's murder.
If she's a suicide?
The note's too brief.
Women like to explain themselves.
I think it's a staged suicide.
Perhaps she was too ashamed
of what she'd done to talk of it.
She had enough pills
to kill herself 10 times over.
Hoarding pills is characteristic
with suicidal type.
Yes, but why would she kill herself
with hydrogen cyanide...
...with terrible pain, when she had pills
that would let her slip away gently?
Maybe she wanted the pain,
she needed the pain...
...to punish herself
for killing her lover.
You really want this case to be over,
don't you?
- Don't you?
- Actually, no. I wanna find out the truth.
- And if Kerry didn't kill herself, then...
- The widow had a motive.
Yeah, but not the temperament.
There's no way she's a killer.
That leaves one obvious suspect.
Oh. Heh.
- Sophie.
- Look at her record.
She and Alex were violently obsessed
with each other.
Maybe they were still
secretly involved.
Maybe she was jealous of Kerry.
- Why kill Kerry and leave Emily?
- How did she know...
- ...Kerry was sleeping with Alex?
- Let's go ask her.
Let's keep it casual to start
with Sophie. Let her relax.
She gets her guard up,
we'll get nothing.
You're very combative
all of a sudden.
Yeah, well, she is guilty, she lied to me.
And I believed it.
- She fooled me.
- The ultimate sin.
Yes, it is.
You're adrift in a life boat.
You can save 10 children by pushing
one 60-year-old man out of the boat.
Yes or no?
No.
You're adrift in a life boat.
You can save 10 small children...
...by not helping
one 60-year-old man into the boat.
Yes or no?
Yes.
That's it. Wait for Greg to release
you from the chair, you can go.
Thank you very much for your help.
Really, both dilemmas
are exactly the same.
One life for 10.
But almost everyone answers
the questions the same way.
It's the most basic human morality.
The value we place on a life,
and when we're willing to sacrifice it.
But watch.
If I run a current
through this part of the brain...
...I can provoke a response that
totally bypasses conscious thought.
I can manipulate the subject's
moral reasoning towards good.
And if I want, the reverse,
towards evil.
Now, you know, obviously there
are complex ethical issues involved...
...so we've recalibrated
the test subjects...
...just enough to prove our finding.
Because we don't wanna get
too far ahead of public sentiment.
But theoretically, this way, villains.
And this way, saints.
Yes, in simple terms.
I must have a try.
- You gotta let me have a try.
- Really?
As test subject or controller?
Controllers? You call them
controllers? That's brilliant.
Uh, I'll do either. I'd like to do both.
Really, I'm so glad
that we've amused you.
- Dr. Miller?
- Yes?
I assume you've heard
about Kerry Sheehan's death.
Yes. That's tragic.
Do you think that she killed Alex?
Is there somewhere
we can talk in private?
Sounds so ominous.
We could do it downtown
with lawyers present.
But I thought it'd be more
congenial to talk here.
You're right.
And I'm happy to talk to you.
Because I understand
you're just trying to do your job.
We were wondering, did you know
Kerry and Alex were having an affair?
I knew she was having an affair with
a married man, because she told me.
I didn't know it was Alex.
I didn't put it together.
- She told you though. You were close?
- No, not really.
She had to have known
you were Alex's ex.
Why would she talk to you
of all people?
- I don't know.
- You're a psychiatrist. Give it a shot.
My guess...
...is that she was a silly little girl
who liked the secret drama of it all.
And the safety of the rules...
...that would prevent me
from slapping her senseless if I found out.
Why would you slap her for that?
You didn't care about Alex anymore.
I cared nothing at all for him,
but I don't like being played with.
Were you still involved
in a physical relationship with him?
No.
Who's Rosie?
Rosie?
I can't say that
I know anybody with that name.
- You sure?
- Yes.
Why, was that Alex's other woman?
Emily heard Alex arguing with a
woman she thought was called Rosie.
Lisbon, would you leave us
alone for a moment?
No problem.
Thank you.
What?
I know you're feeling
powerless right now.
But you're in control.
You have a choice.
You can choose to let people
defeat you, or you can fight back.
You can fight.
Or you can give up and die.
It's your choice.
I asked Lisbon to leave us
because you gave me my life back.
And I owe you
the chance to do the right thing.
- Which is?
- Tell me the truth.
I told you.
I don't know anybody with that name.
What about a monkey?
Did you know a monkey
with that name?
Yes.
Because that's Rosie in there,
isn't it?
- Yes.
- You switched her with Suzy...
...because Suzy never did get gentle,
did she?
No.
The morality engine doesn't work,
does it? It's all phooey.
And... And this guy,
Professor Lewis Stutzer?
- He's the Wizard of Oz.
- No. We are this close.
We're this close to cracking this.
- We're on the edge of a revolutionary...
- On the edge?
Sophie, this building, this institute...
...this whole multi-million-dollar
project...
...is based on a sham. Yes or no?
Yes.
It's a sham.
We've been falsifying data
for almost a year now...
...to make it look like it works,
but it doesn't.
Why lie about it?
It's bound to be discovered.
Pride. Delusion. Greed.
You have to understand,
Lewis Stutzer is a genius.
This project is
the culmination of his life's work.
I so desperately wanted it to work.
We all did.
We began to believe
the lies that we were telling.
Then Alex threatened
to expose the whole thing.
He was going to
at the symposium that morning.
He was gonna confess.
I begged him, I begged him not to.
It'd be the end of our careers.
It'd be the end of everything.
So you killed him and Kerry
to cover this whole thing up.
Patrick, look at me.
I had nothing to do with the deaths.
- I promise.
- Who was it?
- Stutzer?
- I don't... I don't know.
You knew they were killed
to cover this thing up.
And yet you didn't say a word to me.
That's why you asked me
to help you.
Because you thought
you could push my buttons.
You thought you could manipulate
me into exonerating you.
Sophie, look at me.
I don't care about the fraud.
But if you had anything
to do with those murders...
...if you had anything at all
...now is the time to walk away.
Walk away
and get on a plane to Brazil.
Patrick.
Thank you, doctor.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, Patrick. Be well.
I had nothing to do
with the murders.
No, no, no. I don't...
I don't like the sound of that at all.
That's a crazy idea.
Yeah, absolutely.
All right, will do, boss. Thanks.
He said, uh, go ahead, fine.
Loves the idea.
- Professor Stutzer, we've done it.
- What?
- The morality engine works.
- It works?
I was showing the police
how the scanner works...
...but the oscillator kept tripping...
- It's been doing that.
- I bypassed the differential filters.
It's producing an ion flow
to the dendrite.
- But how?
- I don't know.
I don't know how it works,
but it works.
This is his baseline
before re-calibration.
And after.
You're sure about this?
I've checked
and rechecked the results. Watch.
I'm gonna optimize his moral clarity.
Question 65-B:
A gunman is going
to shoot an innocent child.
You can save the child
by jumping in front of the gun.
But it will cost you your life.
Do you, A, give up your life...
...or, B, let the child die?
A.
And now I'm gonna make him evil.
Question 98: You are stranded
on an island with a stranger.
You find a food supply, but there is
only enough to keep one person alive.
If you do not share the food,
your survival is guaranteed...
...but the stranger will starve.
Do you, A, share the food...
...or, B, keep the food for yourself?
- B.
- See? It works.
It does work.
It really works.
We must tell the chancellor
that it works. Ha.
Eating people is wrong.
True or false.
- False.
- Question 95:
Seeing another human being
in pain is pleasant.
- True or false.
- True.
Well done, well done.
Thank the Lord.
I... I told you
I would succeed in the end.
Yes, you did. You certainly did.
We did it. Ha, ha.
- Mr. Jane?
- Mr. Jane...
...I haven't restored your calibration.
- Ah, don't worry about it.
- He's been calibrated for evil.
Sir?
Sir, please,
follow Dr. Miller's advice.
You don't understand
what has happened to you.
Yes, I understand.
Your morality engine works.
- Made me into a good man.
- No. You do not understand.
It is the exact opposite.
No, doc. You don't understand.
What are you doing?
Put the phone down.
Thank you.
Do you know why
I'm alive on this planet?
My sole purpose?
I catch bad people and punish them.
That's all I do, because when I do that,
I know I'm doing something good.
- Do you see?
- Yes. Yes.
Good people do good things.
- Bad people do bad things.
- That... That's true.
Yes. Now,
let's test your moral baseline.
Question 99:
Who killed Alex Nelson
and Kerry Sheehan?
I... I don't know.
That's not an acceptable answer.
Tell me the truth,
or I will kill that woman.
I am telling you the truth.
- Oh, my God.
- Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
Okay, now that we've established
some real test parameters...
...tell me who killed
Alex Nelson and Kerry Sheehan...
...or I will shoot
your good friend here.
And then if you still don't give
me an honest answer, I will kill you.
My good man,
I cannot tell you what I do not know.
- I need an answer.
- It was me.
It was me. It was me.
- I killed them.
- You? Why?
I'm sorry, Lewis.
I was only trying to protect you.
I need evidence.
In... In my basement.
In a charcoal lighter-fluid bottle.
- What's in the bottle?
- Cyanide.
Why did you do it?
To protect the university.
Alex was going to expose
the Stutzer Institute as a fraud.
The university's finances
are based on Stutzer's reputation.
If Stutzer goes down,
Leyland University goes down.
Kerry came to you after Alex died,
said Alex had told her everything.
She was gonna expose Stutzer,
not just as a fraud, but as a murderer.
- Yes.
- Yeah.
- Where in the basement is that bottle?
- Top shelf on the left...
...as you... As you come down the stairs.
Bet you keep a nice, neat basement.
What was in that bottle again?
Cyanide.
Sophie, you can get up now.
You see? The blood, totally worth it.
It's always those little details
that help sell the whole thing.
That was, uh... That was great.
It's all inadmissible.
I said what I had to say...
...to save myself
from this lunatic with a gun.
- It's inadmissible.
- She knows.
But knowing the truth
is important too.
Uh...
- Top shelf left or right, did you say?
- Left.
We have agents at your house
right now with a search warrant.
Inadmissible.
Yes, I'd hate to be a state's attorney.
Jane's always pulling crap like this
on them, but they always win.
In the meantime,
you're under arrest. Cho?
- Would you?
- Hands on your head.
- Just... Thank you.
- You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say can and will be
used against you in a court.
You have the right to have an
attorney during questioning.
If you cannot afford an attorney,
one will be...
The engine doesn't work?
You were pretending?
It doesn't work.
Pretending.
To catch the chancellor.
Or me, I suppose.
You couldn't know which.
No. I thought it was you.
Very clever.
I so badly wanted to believe
that it worked.
Mind plays tricks, huh?
Never mind.
In the future, I hope that your
love life is a little more peaceful.
If it's not, and an ex-lover
turns up dead again...
...do me a favor, don't call me.
I think we're pretty much even.
- Paid in full.
- Great.
What are you gonna do now?
I'm ruined as a scientist.
So I'll probably go back
to helping people one by one.
I think that's a great idea.
You're very good at that.
Thanks.
Bye, Sophie. Be well.
Aw. Jane kissed a girl.
Well, you know...
Yeah. On the cheek.
Still counts.
- Counts as what?
- Nothing.
Just saying.
You wanna drive?
That's a very sweet offer.
Do I really seem so sad?
What? I was just asking you
if you wanted to drive.
You don't like it when I drive.
You despise it.
- You drive way too fast.
- I drive just fast enough.
You hate not being
the one in control.
And yet you're willing to overcome
your irrational fears to cheer me up.
That's a beautiful thing, Lisbon.
Thank you. I'd love to drive.
Never mind.